# **Dean Smith**

14 Manchester Road, Leigh, Greater Manchester WN7 2AZ

Mobile: 07804171583 dean96@live.co.uk

#### **Personal Profile**

I am a reliable and hard-working individual who is dedicated and eager to learn, having a keen eye for detail while able to maintain a fast and organised work pace. Also being self-motivated and always wanting to improve myself, having just completed an independent programming course and passed a Microsoft exam. I work well within a team being a helpful and friendly member of any team and having excellent communication skills, whilst still working equally as well on my own, giving 100% to every task I undertake.

I was previously employed by Hartley Botanic for 2 years where I quickly became a valued member of the team. Due to my abilities, I was entrusted with running the preparation department and training new staff, making sure they adhered to all health and safety regulations and were full competent with working the machinery. Further developing my ability to work to meet tight deadlines as it was frequent to experience busy periods over the year. My most recent employment at Poundstretcher has helped me improve my problem solving and communication skills, expressing and exchanging ideas with colleagues and showing I can maintain a cool head while dealing with unpleasant customers.

As with all my employment history you will find me to be a very organised and punctual person, being highly conscientious and planning out most things around my work and home life. You will also find me to be a fully committed and dedicated member of the team, highly adaptable to different situations and a strong affinity to deliver the best product I can.

### **Education & Qualifications**

#### Parrenthorn High School- 09/2007/2012

#### GCSE:

- Mathematics (B)
- Science (C)
- Physical Education (C)
- Product design (D)
- English (C)
- Religious Education (D)
- Geography (**D**)

•

#### Bury College - 09/2012-07/2014

**B-Tec:** Extended diploma in applied science (**DDM**)

#### **Employment History**

Jan 2015 – March 2018 Hartley Botanic

- Operating a crane to take inventories
- Preparing the metal to be dipped
- Using a crane to dip the orders through a cleaner and coater before drying
- Maintaining a neat and tidy workspace
- Keeping track of multiple different orders
- Working under pressure to meet tight deadlines
- Training new employees
- Inspecting completed items for any imperfections
- · Helping other areas of the factory when understaffed
- Wrapping and packaging orders
- Delivering orders

# March 2018 – Current Poundstretcher

- Operating the till system
- Answering telephone calls
- Taking deliveries
- Accurately pricing and organising new stock
- Refilling shelves with stock
- Keeping the shop floor tidy
- Directing and advising customers
- Tilling up, counting cash and ensuring the accuracy of sales
- Dealing with short tempered customers
- Delegating
- Training new staff

## **Hobbies & Interests**

I enjoy many different activities such as playing sports with friends, going out for a meal and drinks, or even just sitting at my computer listening to music and playing games. My two biggest hobbies being sports and video games, captaining my football team for 9 years throughout my school years where we gained two promotions and made it to a cup final. Having made many friends over the years through gaming, even having one friend come over from America too visit back in 2019.

- Walking my dog
- Going to the gym
- Video games
- Binge watching tv shows
- Going out for food
- Hiking

- Listening to Music
- Playing sports
- Day out activities
- Psychology
- Astrophysics, Rockets, and stargazing
- Reading

#### References

Rachel Wilkinson
 College biology
 teacher
 Woodbury Centre, Market St,
 Bury BL9 0BG
 <u>Rachel.Wilkinson@burycollege.ac.uk</u>
 01612808280

Marie Marvel
Manager at Poundstretcher
Contact details available upon
request